<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-18T14:30:12+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><subtitle>Dwell in possibility</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Explanations of modern quantum theory</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/explanations-of-quantum-mechanics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Explanations of modern quantum theory" /><published>2016-11-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/explanations-of-quantum-mechanics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/explanations-of-quantum-mechanics/">&lt;p&gt;Since different branches of physics have established during last century, it turns out that quantum physics has become a more and more important tool to solve various kinds physics problem. However, as Einstein pointed out the photon hypothesis of light, many explanation to quantum mechanics have also been put forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all is the Schrodinger’s wave function, which is most popular theory among the earliest quantum physicists. According to this theory, wave and particle are both essential for quantum phenomenon. When a beam of light emitted from laser cavity, it behaves like plat wave, which take the form of triangle function multiplied by an time harmonic factor. On contrast with classic assumption, when it comes to split experiment, light can act like particle and it seems that it will follow some certain path, which we call path of particle and the path is the range of the calculation to keep the total possibility that particle will appear, in other words, be measured and collapse to a certain state, is normalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another theory was funded by Heisenberg at his twenties. He thought that when we take measurement of quantum system, the particle or wave will collapse to a state and the quantum state have the certain amplitudes, which indicates that each received state will be one part of the previous state. However, due to uncertainty law, we have no information of which state we will get from the measurement. After several mathematical abstract summary, this opinion was develop  as matrix theory of quantum physics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last theory may a little later than previous two, it was Feynman’s path calculus theory. As we discussed above, if we consider quantum state as particle, only the possible paths will be satisfied and different mechanical and dynamical functions can be expressed by a simple calculus of those paths. This idea is much more modern and sometimes more useful when you handle a complicated physics model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, confusion are always coexisting with development, especially topics of modern physics. In order to figure out all the universe mysteries, we are supposed to keep expanding the boundary of physics.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="quantum mechanics" /><summary type="html">Since different branches of physics have established during last century, it turns out that quantum physics has become a more and more important tool to solve various kinds physics problem. However, as Einstein pointed out the photon hypothesis of light, many explanation to quantum mechanics have also been put forward.</summary></entry></feed>